Charles F. Johnson Jr. Papers
Charles F. Johnson Jr. Papers
1899-1959
Johnson, Charles F., 1887-1959.
136 linear feet
Papers of the American business executive. Collection includes Correspondence, including notices and memorandums to workers and staff (1918-1959); manuscripts (1934-1956); material relating to the George F. Johnson, Jr., Memorial Fund (1948-1951); photographs and photograph albums (1899-1958); plaques (1935-1957); clippings of the Workers' Pages from the Binghamton Sun (1948-1956); petitions signed by the workers (1946-1956); clippings, press releases, articles, advertisements, and brochures (1916-1959); and scrapbooks (1947-1957).
146298
Biographical History
Charles F. Johnson, Jr. (1887-1959) was an American businessman and entrepreneur in Binghamton, New York.
Charles F. Johnson, Jr. was born in Binghamton, New York on Oct. 22, 1887. He grew up in Johnson City, N.Y., where some of his early playmates were Endicott-Johnson workers' children. His father, C. Fred Johnson, was the brother of George F. Johnson, a co-founder of the Endicott-Johnson Shoe Corporation. Charles Johnson, Jr. graduated from Mercersburg Academy in 1905, and soon after took his place at the bench in the Boys' and Youths' Factory. He became factory superintendent in 1913, and upon his uncle George's resignation in 1930, became vice-president and general manager of the Endicott-Johnson Corporation. From 1948 to 1957 he was elected chairman of the board.
Mr. Johnson served as vice-president and director of the National Shoe Manufacturers Association, was director of Marine Midland Trust Co. of Southern N.Y., and director of Mohawk Airlines. Active in community affairs, Mr. Johnson was instrumental in the establishment of Harpur College at Binghamton, N.Y. One of the awards Mr. Johnson received was the L.L.D. Award from Colgate University, 1952. When Charles F. Johnson, Jr. died on August 9, 1959, he was survived by his wife, Jeanette, and two daughters, Jeanette Tunnicliff, and Patricia Luckie.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Charles F. Johnson, Jr. Papers include correspondence, manuscripts, photographs, photo albums, scrapbooks, plaques, workers' petitions, published material, scrapbooks, and miscellany.
Correspondence includes incoming and outgoing letters, memorandums and telegrams. Most of the correspondence from George F. Johnson is signed with a stamped signature and many are carbon copies of letters sent to George W. Johnson. Included in the outgoing correspondence are typescript and mimeographed notices or memorandums to workers and staff.
Subject files includes correspondence, published material, scrapbooks, movie reels and tapes.
Manuscripts consist of manuscripts about and by Charles F. Johnson, Jr., a manuscript about Endicott-Johnson Corp. and manuscripts of others.
Material relating to the George F. Johnson, Jr. Memorial Fund consists of incoming and outgoing correspondence, minutes of meetings, financial papers and published material.
Photographs consist of photographs arranged alphabetically by subject.
Photograph albums are arranged chronologically for the photographs that are general in nature. Albums of a particular subject are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Plaques are those received by Mr. Johnson.
Workers' Pages consist of full page clippings from the Binghamton Sun. This page appeared daily and was devoted to news about Endicott-Johnson workers.
Workers' petitions include petitions signed by Endicott-Johnson workers thanking Mr. Johnson for various benefits (vacations, bonuses).
Published material includes advertisements, brochures, articles, newspaper clippings, notices and press releases arranged alphabetically by type.
Scrapbooks contains numerous scrapbooks on various topics as well as several that are general in nature.
Miscellaneous material, all oversize, includes a phonograph record, a photograph, a pen and ink painting, award placques and photographs, and some documents.
Arrangement of the Collection
Incoming correspondence is arranged alphabetically by author and outgoing is arranged chronologically. Correspondence of others is arranged alphabetically. Subject files are arranged alphabetically by subject. Manuscripts are arranged alphabetically by type. Memorial Fund material is separated into correspondence and other, both arranged alphabetically. Photographs and albums on specific topics are arranged alphabetically by subject; albums with general photographs are arranged chronologically by the first date in the album. Workers' Pages, Worker's petitions, and published material are arranged chronologically.
Related Material
See also the
George F. Johnson Papers
Frank A. Johnson Papers
George W. Johnson Papers
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; New York State; Johnson, Charles F., 1887-1959.; Johnson, Frank A. 1908-; Johnson, George F., 1857-1948.; Johnson, George Willis, 1880-1953.; Endicott Johnson Corporation -- Employees.; Endicott Johnson Corporation -- History, Sources.; Binghamton sun (Binghamton, N.Y.: Daily); Chief executive officers -- New York (State); Employee morale.; Industries, New York (State) -- Endicott.; Executives, New York (State); Footwear industry -- New York (State); Shoe industry -- Employees.; Shoe industry -- New York (State); Advertising fliers.; Articles.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Financial records.; Manuscripts (document genre); Memorandums.; Minutes (administrative records); Notes (documents); Pamphlets.; Petitions.; Photographs.; Plaques (flat objects); Press releases.; Publications.; Scrapbooks.; Chief executive officers.; Executives.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - Ab-Al, 1918; 1948-1955 (Box 1)
    - Adams, Sherman, 1954; 1957,; 1958 (Box 1)
    - Aiken, George D. (Senator), 1957 (Box 1)
    - Allum, Ralph, 1943; 1945-1947 (Box 1)
    - American A-American W., 1943; 1950-1956 (Box 1)
    - American Appraisal Co., 1954; 1955 (Box 1)
    - American Legion, 1937; 1938,; 1948,; 1950,; 1952-1955 (Box 1)
    - American Red Cross, 1953-1955 (Box 1)
    - America's-Au, 1939; 1942,; 1948,; 1950,; 1952-1955,; 1958 (Box 1)
    - Archbald Enterprise Association, 1946-1949; 1952 (Box 1)
    - Ba-Be, 1918; 1932,; 1937-1939,; 1947,; 1948,; 1950-1955,; 1957 (Box 2)
    - Babcock, Bruck L., 1926; 1930-1933,; 1935,; 1936,; 1938,; 1941-1955,; undated (Box 2)
    - Baruch, Bernard M. Jr., 1956; 1957 (Box 2)
    - Bata Shoe Manufacturing Co., 1938; 1952-1955 (Box 2)
    - Belk Stores, 1953-1955 (Box 2)
    - Benson, Ezra Taft, 1958 (Box 2)
    - Berry, George L. (Senator), 1937 (Box 2)
    - Bi-Bo, 1926; 1937,; 1939,; 1943,; 1944,; 1948-1950,; 1956 (Box 2)
    - Bibby, Dause L., 1949; 1951-1953 (Box 2)
    - Bible, Alan (Senator), 1958 (Box 2)
    - Bilbo, Theodore G. (Senator), 1937 (Box 2)
    - Binghamton Chamber of Commerce, 1937; 1951-1955 (Box 2)
    - Bixby, R. Burdell, 1949; 1951,; 1954 (Box 2)
    - Boigeol, Marion, 1946; 1947,; 1950-1951,; 1954,; 1955 (Box 2)
    - Br-Bu, 1918; 1937,; 1947,; 1948,; 1950-1956 (Box 2)
    - Bricker, John W. (Senator), 1954; 1958 (Box 2)
    - Broome County Airport, 1952; 1953,; 1955 (Box 2)
    - Broome County Civil Defense, 1952-1954 (Box 2)
    - Broome County Technical Institute, 1953; 1954,; 1956 (Box 2)
    - Broome County United Fund, 1954 (Box 2)
    - Brunswick-Balke Collender Co., 1952; 1955,; 1956 (Box 2)
    - Burns, J. Runyon, 1926; 1927,; undated (Box 2)
    - Bush, Prescott (Senator), 1955; 1958 (Box 2)
    - Butler, John Marshall (Senator), 1958 (Box 2)
    - Ca-Cl, 1930; 1936,; 1937,; 1943,; 1945-1956 (Box 3)
    - Capehart, Sen. Homer, 1958 (Box 3)
    - Capper, Sen. Arthur, 1937 (Box 3)
    - Caraway, Sen. Hattie, 1937 (Box 3)
    - Carey, Robert B., 1949-1951; 1953,; 1954 (Box 3)
    - Case, Everett, 1952; 1955,; 1956 (Box 3)
    - Case, Francis (Senator), 1958 (Box 3)
    - Chavez, Dennis (Senator), 1958 (Box 3)
    - Clark, Bennett Champ (Senator), 1937 (Box 3)
    - Co-Cu, 1918; 1936,; 1937,; 1948-1956 (Box 3)
    - Cole, Congressman Sterling, 1953; 1954 (Box 3)
    - The Committee for One Million, 1953; 1954,; 1956,; undated (Box 3)
    - Copeland, Royal S. (Senator), 1937 (Box 3)
    - Costello, E. J., 1948; 1951-1953 (Box 3)
    - Cotton, Norris (Senator), 1958 (Box 3)
    - Curtis, Carl T. (Senator), 1958 (Box 3)
    - D, 1918; 1932,; 1937,; 1938,; 1944,; 1946-1956 (Box 3)
    - Daniel Green Co., 1950 (Box 3)
    - Day, Edmund E., 1949 (Box 3)
    - Dedication of Endicott-Johnson Recreation Bldg., 1949 (Box 3)
    - Dewey, Thomas E. (Governor), 1953; 1954 (Box 4)
    - Dickson, W. F., 1925; 1927,; 1929,; 1930 (Box 4)
    - Diekroeger, F. E., 1949; 1950,; 1954 (Box 4)
    - Dirksen, Everett M. (Senator), 1957; 1958 (Box 4)
    - Donahey, Vic (Senator), 1937 (Box 4)
    - Dulles, John Foster, 1955 (Box 4)
    - Dworshak, Henry (Senator), 1958 (Box 4)
    - E, 1918; 1926,; 1937,; 1946-1951,; 1953-1955 (Box 4)
    - Eastern Tool and Stamping Co., 1944-1946 (Box 4)
    - Eccleston, Howard B., 1948; 1949,; 1952,; 1954,; 1955 (Box 4)
    - Eckelberger, Robert L., 1932; 1945-1951,; 1952-1955,; 1957; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Endicott, H. Wendell, 1922; 1953 (Box 4)
    - F, 1918; 1939,; 1946,; 1948-1956,; 1958 (Box 4)
    - Feeck, W. D., 1953-1955 (Box 4)
    - Ford, Benson, 1953 (Box 4)
    - Frank A. Johnson American Legion Memorial, Inc., 1954 (Box 4)
    - Fulbright, J. W. (Senator), 1958 (Box 4)
    - Ga-Gen, 1918; 1947-1956 (Box 5)
    - Geo-Gl, 1948-1957 (Box 5)
    - George F. Johnson Memorial Fund, 1950; 1951 (Box 5)
    - Gillette, Guy M. (Senator), 1951 (Box 5)
    - Go-Gu, 1918; 1931,; 1945,; 1947-1956,; 1959 (Box 5)
    - The H. C. Godman Co., 1937; 1948,; 1950,; 1955 (Box 5)
    - Goldman, Sachs & Co., 1943; 1948-1950,; 1951-1953,; 1955 (Box 5)
    - B. F. Goodrich Co., 1951 (Box 6)
    - Graves, Guy Jr., 1951; 1954 (Box 6)
    - Greater Endicott Chamber of Commerce, 1951-1954 (Box 6)
    - Greater Endicott Community Chest, 1952-1954 (Box 6)
    - Green, Theodore Francis (Senator), 1958 (Box 6)
    - Griswold, Lulu, 1945; 1948,; 1950,; 1951 (Box 6)
    - Guffey, Joseph F. (Senator), 1937 (Box 6)
    - Ha, 1918; 1932,; 1938,; 1943,; 1948-1955 (Box 6)
    - Hall, Edwin Arthur (Congressman), 1949-1951 (Box 6)
    - Hankin's Container Co., 1949-1951 (Box 6)
    - Harpur College, 1948-1955 (Box 6)
      See also Triple Cities College
    - Harrison, Coughlin, Dermody & Ingalls, 1952 (Box 6)
    - He-Hy, 1918; 1936,; 1945-1956,; 1958 (Box 6)
    - Hennings, Thomas C. Jr. (Senator), 1958 (Box 6)
    - Herald Tribune Fresh Air Fund, 1952-1954; 1956 (Box 6)
    - Hershey, L. V., 1948; 1950-1952 (Box 6)
    - Hester, Christian, 1955 (Box 6)
    - Hester, Joseph P., 1948-1953; 1955 (Box 6)
    - Hill, William H., 1936; 1951-1953,; 1955,; undated (Box 6)
    - Hinman, Howard & Kattell, 1948; 1949,; 1951-1955 (Box 7)
    - Hogan, W.J., 1931-1934; 1937-1942,; undated (Box 7)
    - Holland, Spessard L. (Senator), 1958 (Box 7)
    - Huntington Press Inc., 1935 (Box 7)
    - I, 1935; 1949-1955 (Box 7)
    - International Business Machine Corp., 1948-1955 (Box 7)
      See also Watson, Thomas and Watson, Thomas Jr.
    - International Shoe Mfg. Co., 1937; 1949-1951,; 1954,; 1955 (Box 7)
    - Ives, Irving M. (Senator), 1948; 1949,; 1951,; 1953-1955,; 1958,; undated (Box 7)
    - J, 1926; 1927,; 1937,; 1944-1946,; 1948,; 1956 (Box 8)
    - Jackson, Henry M. (Senator), 1958 (Box 8)
    - Jenner, William E. (Senator), 1957 (Box 8)
    - Johnson, C. Fred (CFW's father), 1926; 1927,; undated (Box 8)
    - Johnson, Frank A., 1945; 1946,; 1953,; 1957 (Box 8)
    - Johnson, George F.
      - 1918, 1922, 1923 (Box 8)
      - 1926: February-April, June, August, September, November, December, 2 folders (Box 8)
      - 1927, 3 folders (Box 8)
      - 1928, 3 folders (Box 9)
      - 1929, 5 folders (Box 9)
      - 1930, 5 folders (Box 10)
      - 1931: January-September, November-December, 4 folders (Box 10)
      - 1932, 2 folders (Box 10)
      - 1933: January-May, July-September, November-December, 2 folders (Box 11)
      - 1934: January-April, June-December, 2 folders (Box 11)
      - 1935: January-April, July-December, 2 folders (Box 11)
      - 1936: January-March (Box 11)
      - 1936: May, July-December (Box 12)
      - 1937 (Box 12)
      - 1938 (Box 12)
      - 1939 (Box 12)
      - 1943, 1944, 1946, 1947, 1948 (Box 12)
    - Johnson, George W.
      - 1926, 1927, 1930-1933, 4 folders (Box 12)
      - 1934-1947, 1949, 1951-1952, undated, 5 folders (Box 13)
    - Johnson, Harold, 1950-1953 (Box 14)
    - Johnson, Louis, 1949 (Box 14)
    - Johnson, Walter, 1949; 1950,; 1954 (Box 14)
    - Johnson City Chamber of Commerce, 1949; 1950,; 1952,; 1954,; 1955 (Box 14)
    - Johnson City Community Chest, Inc., 1950; 1952-1955 (Box 14)
    - Johnston, Sen. Olin D., 1958 (Box 14)
    - Jones and Vining, 1945; 1949,; 1950,; 1955 (Box 14)
    - Ka-Ke, 1944; 1948-1952,; 1954-1955 (Box 14)
    - Karl's Kustom Made Shoes, 1950-1952 (Box 14)
    - Victor Kayfetz Productions, Inc., 1953-1955 (Box 14)
    - Kefauver, Estes (Senator), 1958 (Box 14)
    - Kennedy, John F. (Senator), 1957 (Box 14)
    - Keogh, Eugene J. (Congressman), 1951 (Box 14)
    - Kern, George, 1955 (Box 14)
    - Keystone State Shoe Co., 1947; 1948,; 1952,; 1953,; 1955 (Box 14)
    - Ki-Ku, 1938; 1941,; 1947-1955 (Box 14)
    - G. R. Kinney Co., Inc., 1953; 1954 (Box 14)
    - Knapp, Frank C., 1946-1948; 1950,; 1952,; 1954,; 1955 (Box 14)
    - Kress, Charles, 1958 (Box 14)
    - La-Le, 1918; 1937,; 1942,; 1948-1955 (Box 15)
    - Lausche, Frank J. (Senator), 1957; 1958 (Box 15)
    - Lehman, Herbert H. (Senator), 1951; 1953-1955 (Box 15)
    - Li-Ly, 1918; 1937,; 1942,; 1945,; 1947-1956 (Box 15)
    - Liberty Shoe Stores, 1954 (Box 15)
    - Link Aviation Co., 1945; 1948,; 1951,; 1953-1955 (Box 15)
    - Litterer, Harvey, 1953-1955 (Box 15)
    - Lombard, Arline, 1943-1946; undated (Box 15)
    - Lonergan, Augustine (Senator), 1937 (Box 15)
    - Lord, Bert (Congressman), 1937 (Box 15)
    - Lord, Chester B., 1926; 1927 (Box 15)
    - Ma, 1930; 1937,; 1948-1955,; 1957 (Box 15)
    - Mansfield, Mike (Senator), 1957 (Box 15)
    - March of Dimes (Box 15)
    - Marine Corps League, 1950; 1951 (Box 15)
    - Marine Midland Trust Co., 1948-1951; 1953-1955 (Box 15)
    - Martin, Edward, 1945; 1951 (Box 15)
    - Mc-Me, 1918; 1937 (Box 16)
    - McClellan, Sen. John L., 1958 (Box 16)
    - McCormack, John W. (Congressman), 1937; 1957 (Box 16)
    - McNamara, Pat (Senator), 1958 (Box 16)
    - Merle, Lawrence, 1926; 1928,; 1942-1955 (Box 16)
    - Mi-My, 1937; 1947-1951,; 1953-1955,; 1957 (Box 16)
    - Mills, Leo E. (Vice-Pres.), 1933; 1940-1954 (Box 16)
    - Mitchell, James P., 1955 (Box 16)
    - Mohawk Airlines, 1953-1954; 1957 (Box 16)
    - Molter, Carl, Sr., 1946-1948; 1952,; 1954; mimeo memos (Box 16)
    - Moore, A. Harry (Senator), 1937 (Box 16)
    - Morris, L. G., 1953-1955 (Box 16)
    - Morse, Wayne (Senator), 1958 (Box 16)
    - Murphy, Charles F., 1949; 1953-1957 (Box 16)
    - Murray, Joseph C., 1949; 1951,; 1952,; 1954-1955 (Box 16)
    - Na, 1948-1951; 1953-1956 (Box 17)
    - National Associated Businessmen Inc., 1954-1956 (Box 17)
    - National Association of Manufacturers, 1949-1951; 1953 (Box 17)
    - National Boot and Shoe Manufacturers Association, 1935; 1937,; 1938 (Box 17)
    - National Council for Community Improvement, 1948; 1952 (Box 17)
    - National Fund for Medical Education, 1953-1955 (Box 17)
    - National Hide Association, 1954; 1955 (Box 17)
    - National Industrial Conference Board, 1949-1951; 1955 (Box 17)
    - National Polychemicals, Inc., 1953 (Box 17)
    - National Service Bureau, 1954; 1955 (Box 17)
    - National Shoe Foundation for Disabled Feet, 1949; 1950,; 1952,; 1953 (Box 17)
    - National Shoe Manufacturers Association, 1949-1952; 1954,; 1955,; undated (Box 17)
    - Ne-No, 1937; 1938,; 1948-1950,; 1952-1955,; 1958 (Box 18)
    - Neiley, Jewett F., 1937; 1946,; 1948,; 1954,; 1955 (Box 18)
    - New England Shoe and Leather Association, 1937 (Box 18)
    - New Jersey National Guard, 1949; 1950 (Box 18)
    - New York Board of Trade, 1951 (Box 18)
    - New York National Guard, 1940; 1949-1955 (Box 18)
    - Nixon, Richard, 1955 (Box 18)
    - Nolc, George, 1952; 1953,; 1955 (Box 18)
    - O, 1932; 1942,; 1949-1951,; 1954-1955 (Box 18)
    - Pa-Pe, 1927; 1933,; 1947-1956 (Box 18)
    - Pacific Mills, 1948; 1950,; 1951,; 1953 (Box 18)
    - Pastore, John O. (Senator), 1958 (Box 18)
    - Payne, Frederick G., 1958 (Box 18)
    - Perry, Ray, 1948-1951 (Box 18)
    - Ph-Pr, 1927; 1937,; 1938,; 1944,; 1946,; 1950,; 1951,; 1953-1955 (Box 18)
    - Phillips, John G., 1949-1951; undated (Box 18)
    - Powell, Clyde R., 1935; 1936,; 1938,; 1940-1945; carbons (Box 18)
    - Q, Ra-Ri, 1918; 1937,; 1938,; 1941,; 1947-1955,; 1957 (Box 18)
    - Radcliffe College, 1949-1951 (Box 19)
    - Ro-Ry, 1948-1956 (Box 19)
    - Robertson, Willis A. (Senator), 1958 (Box 19)
    - Rogers, William P., 1958; copy (Box 19)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1937 (Box 19)
    - Sa-Se, 1943; 1946-1958 (Box 19)
    - Salem, Herman R., 1926; 1945,; 1947,; 1949,; 1951-1954 (Box 19)
    - Schoeppel, Andrew (Senator), 1958 (Box 19)
    - Sears-Roebuck, 1948-1952; 1954,; 1955 (Box 19)
    - Seligman & Seligman
      - 1945, 1947, 1948-1950, 2 folders (Box 19)
      - 1951-1954, 4 folders (Box 20)
      - 1955, undated (Box 21)
    - Servicemen, 1940-1944; 1946,; 1953-1956; 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Sh-Sl, 1937; 1943,; 1948-1952,; 1954,; 1955 (Box 21)
    - Sheperd, General Lemuel C. Jr., 1953 (Box 21)
    - Slater System, Inc., 1952-1955 (Box 21)
    - Smith, H. Alexander (Senator), 1958 (Box 21)
    - Solnit Shoe Co., 1951-1953 (Box 21)
    - Sordoni Construction Co., 1946; 1949,; 1950 (Box 21)
    - Sn-Sp, 1938; 1944,; 1949-1956 (Box 22)
    - Sparkman, John (Senator), 1958 (Box 22)
    - St-Sy, 1932; 1941,; 1946,; 1947,; 1949-1957 (Box 22)
    - Stanford, Linda, 1932; 1934-1935,; 1938-1941,; 1943-1956,; undated; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - State of New York, 1949-1955 (Box 22)
    - State of Tennessee, 1941; 1950,; 1951,; 1953,; 1954 (Box 22)
    - State University of New York, 1950; 1951,; 1953-1955 (Box 22)
    - Stennis, John (Senator), 1958 (Box 23)
    - Sullivan County Industrial Corp., 1946; 1947 (Box 23)
    - Susquehanna Valley Home, 1950-1952; 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Swartwood, Howard A., 1937; 1940,; 1942,; 1944-1956; undated; 3 folders (Box 23)
    - Sweet, Lillian Johnson, 1949; 1954 (Box 23)
      See also George F. Johnson Memorial Fund: Sweet, Lillian Johnson
    - T, 1918; 1937,; 1942,; 1943,; 1949-1958 (Box 24)
    - Taber, John (Congressman), 1958 (Box 24)
    - Tallman, O. J., 1945; 1948 (Box 24)
    - Tax Foundation, 1949; 1950,; 1954 (Box 24)
    - Thurmond, Strom (Senator), 1958 (Box 24)
    - Thye, Edward J. (Senator), 1958 (Box 24)
    - Tolley, William P., 1950 (Box 24)
    - Touche, Niven & Co., 1931-1937; 1939,; 1940,; 1946-1949,; 1952,; 1955,; undated; 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Transportation Association of America, 1950-1954 (Box 24)
    - Triple Cities College (Box 24)
      See also Harpur College.
    - Triple Cities Traction Corporation, 1954; 1955 (Box 24)
    - Truman, Harry S., 1951; mimeo (Box 24)
    - Turner, Arthur N., 1951 (Box 24)
    - U, 1943; 1948-1951,; 1953-1956 (Box 25)
    - Ulio, Major Gen. J. A., 1943 (Box 25)
    - United Shoe Machinery Corp., 1937; 1939,; 1945,; 1949,; 1950,; 1952-1955 (Box 25)
    - United States Dept. of Commerce, 1937; 1948,; 1950,; 1954,; 1955 (Box 25)
    - United States Dept. of Labor, 1935; 1936,; 1939,; 1941,; 1945-1956; 4 folders (Box 25)
    - University of Rochester, School of Medicine & Dentistry, 1944-1948; 1950-1957; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - V, 1949-1951; 1953-1955,; 1958 (Box 26)
    - Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Senator), 1937 (Box 26)
    - Van Patten, Cornelius, 1953-1956 (Box 26)
    - Veterans of Foreign Wars, 1951-1953; 1955 (Box 26)
    - Village of Johnson City Water Dept., 1938; 1949,; 1953,; undated (Box 26)
    - Wa-We, 1918; 1937,; 1941,; 1943-1948,; 1950-1956,; 1958 (Box 26)
    - Wadsworth, Congressman James W., 1937 (Box 27)
    - War Department - Boston Quartermaster Corps., 1935 (Box 27)
    - Watson, Thomas, 1937; 1948-1954,; 1956,; undated (Box 27)
      See also International Business Machine
    - Watson, Thomas Jr., 1949-1955; undated (Box 27)
    - Weeks, Sinclair, 1958 (Box 27)
    - Wh-Wy, 1918; 1931,; 1937,; 1943,; 1947-1955,; 1958 (Box 27)
    - White, Wallace H. (Senator), 1937 (Box 27)
    - Wilson, Charles E., 1953; 1956,; 1957 (Box 27)
    - Wold, William C., 1953-1955 (Box 27)
    - Worcester Shoe Co., 1954 (Box 27)
    - Y-Z, 1945; 1948,; 1951-1955 (Box 27)
    - Young, Milton R. (Senator), 1957; 1958 (Box 27)
    - Y. M. C. A. of Binghamton, N. Y., 1951-1955
    - Workers, Anonymous, 1935-1938; 1943,; 1947-1948,; 1950-1955,; undated (Box 27)
    - Unidentified, 1918; 1927,; 1933-1935,; 1937,; 1947,; 1950-1952,; 1954 (Box 27)
  - Outgoing
    - 1926: January-April, November, 3 folders (Box 28)
    - 1927: January-April, August-November, 4 foldesr (Box 28)
    - 1928: January-May, July-December, 5 folders (Box 28)
    - 1929: January-May, July, September-December, 5 folders (Box 28)
    - 1930, 8 folders (Box 28)
    - 1931, 5 folders (Box 29)
    - 1932, 6 folders (Box 29)
    - 1933, 8 folders (Box 29)
    - 1934, 6 folders (Box 30)
    - 1935, 10 folders (Box 30)
    - 1936, 12 folders (Box 31)
    - 1937, 12 folders (Box 31)
    - 1938, 12 folders (Box 32)
    - 1939 January-September, November, December, 3 folders (Box 32)
    - 1940, 2 folders (Box 32)
    - 1941, 2 folders (Box 33)
    - 1942, 3 folders (Box 33)
    - 1943, 4 folders (Box 33)
    - 1944 (Box 34)
    - 1945, 6 folders (Box 34)
    - 1946, 5 folders (Box 34)
    - 1947, 2 folders (Box 34)
    - 1948, 3 folders (Box 35)
    - 1949, 4 folders (Box 35)
    - 1950, 4 folders (Box 36)
    - 1951, 3 folders (Box 36)
    - 1952, 3 folders (Box 37)
    - 1953, 4 folders (Box 37)
    - 1954, 6 folders (Box 38)
    - 1955, 7 folders (Box 39)
    - 1956 (Box 40)
    - 1957, 1958, 1959, undated (Box 40)
  - Of others
    - Callahan, Leo, 1952; 1954,; 1955 (Box 40)
    - Scrapbook of Letters, 1931; 1934-1937 (Box 40)
      See also Subject files: Scrapbook and Scrapbooks series
- Subject File
  - Airplane (Endicott-Johnson Corp. Private Plane), 1951-1955 (Box 41)
  - American Legion, 1938; 1954,; 1955 (Box 41)
  - Army Shoes, 1927; 1933-1935 (Box 41)
  - Automatic Sprinkler System, 1955 (Box 41)
  - Awards, E.-J. Corp., 1950; 1957,; undated (Box 41)
  - Bata Shoe Co., 1937; 1946 (Box 41)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1936; 1945,; 1950,; 1951,; 1953-1955 (Box 41)
  - Blueprint, 1945; 1947 (Box 41)
  - Bonus, 1955; 1956 (Box 41)
  - Boot and Shoe Workers Union, 1938 (Box 41)
  - Broome County Safety Council, 1946; 1947,; 1954 (Box 41)
  - Broome County United Fund, 1953-1955 (Box 41)
  - Calling Cards, undated (Box 41)
  - C. Fred Johnson, 1954 (Box 41)
  - Charles F. Johnson Elementary School, 1955 (Box 42)
  - Charles F. Johnson 50th Anniversary Celebration, 1955 (Box 42)
  - Colgate University Degree, 1952 (Box 42)
  - Collective Bargaining, Transcript of Meeting, 1952 (Box 42)
  - Community Chest, 1952 (Box 42)
  - Crime Prevention, undated (Box 42)
  - Death of C. F. J. Jr., August; 1959 (Box 42)
  - Defense Plant Corporation
    - 1943-1945, 2 folders (Box 42)
    - 1946-1948, undated (Box 43)
  - F. C. Donovan, Inc., 1952 (Box 43)
  - Drawing of Charles F. Johnson, Jr., undated (Box 43)
  - Dun and Bradstreet Reports, 1950; 1952,; 1953 (Box 43)